[
  {
    "question": "105. The 'load' means the following?",
    "choices": [
      "Specified pressure an air tire can carry.",
      "The maximum safe weight a tire can carry at a specified pressure.",
      "Neither of these answers are correct."
    ],
    "answer": "The maximum safe weight a tire can carry at a specified pressure."
  },
  {
    "question": "106. Whether or not you load and secure your load yourself, you are responsible for:",
    "choices": [
      "Knowing your cargo is securely tied-down and covered.",
      "Recognizing overloads and poorly balanced weight.",
      "Inspecting your cargo.",
      "All of these answers are correct."
    ],
    "answer": "All of these answers are correct."
  },
  {
    "question": "107. Which of these statements about downshifting for a long downhill grade is true?",
    "choices": [
      "The proper time to downshift is just after the vehicle starts down the hill.",
      "It allows engine compression and friction to help the brakes slow the vehicle.",
      "It should not be done with automatic transmissions."
    ],
    "answer": "It allows engine compression and friction to help the brakes slow the vehicle."
  },
  {
    "question": "108. Medical certificates must be renewed every:",
    "choices": ["2 years.", "9 months.", "4 years."],
    "answer": "2 years."
  },
  {
    "question": "109. During a pre-trip inspection you discover an exhaust leak or power steering leak, you should:",
    "choices": [
      "Report the problem and make arrangements for another vehicle to use.",
      "Go home because you shouldn't drive the vehicle this way.",
      "Note the problem and continue your route."
    ],
    "answer": "Report the problem and make arrangements for another vehicle to use."
  },
  {
    "question": "110. During what time in your pre-trip inspection of a school bus do you check the back emergency door? (to ensure it is closed.)",
    "choices": [
      "During step four (lights first half) the inside walk through.",
      "Only during the operation inspection of the pre-trip.",
      "Only during the inside walk through."
    ],
    "answer": "During step four (lights first half) the inside walk through."
  },
  {
    "question": "111. Inspect your cargo after you have driven:",
    "choices": [
      "25 miles or 50 miles depending on the law in the state you are in, then again after 3 hours or after you have driven 150 miles and after every stop for a break.",
      "75 miles.",
      "150 miles."
    ],
    "answer": "25 miles or 50 miles depending on the law in the state you are in, then again after 3 hours or after you have driven 150 miles and after every stop for a break."
  },
  {
    "question": "112. Axle weight means the following?",
    "choices": [
      "The weight transmitted to the ground by one axle or one set of axles.",
      "The weight transmitted to the tires from the axle.",
      "Both of these are correct."
    ],
    "answer": "The weight transmitted to the ground by one axle or one set of axles."
  },
  {
    "question": "113. Blocking your cargo to keep it from sliding must be done at the:",
    "choices": [
      "Needed in the front of a piece of cargo only.",
      "Unattached to the cargo deck.",
      "Used in front, back, and/or sides of a piece of cargo."
    ],
    "answer": "Used in front, back, and/or sides of a piece of cargo."
  },
  {
    "question": "114. Over-length, over-width, and/or overweight loads require:",
    "choices": [
      "Flashing lights.",
      "Driving limited to certain times.",
      "Special transit permits.",
      "All of these answers are correct."
    ],
    "answer": "All of these answers are correct."
  },
  {
    "question": "115. Turn signals should be used:",
    "choices": [
      "At least 100 feet before turning or changing lanes.",
      "At least 250 feet before turning or changing lanes.",
      "At least 350 feet before turning or changing lanes."
    ],
    "answer": "At least 100 feet before turning or changing lanes."
  },
  {
    "question": "116. Which of these statements about speed management is true?",
    "choices": [
      "On a wet road, you should reduce your speed by about 1/3.",
      "On packed snow, you should reduce your speed by about 1/2.",
      "When the road is slippery, it will take longer to stop and it will be harder to turn without skidding.",
      "All of these are true."
    ],
    "answer": "All of these are true."
  },
  {
    "question": "117. You are driving on a straight, level highway at 50 mph. There are no vehicles in front of you. Suddenly a tire blows out on your vehicle. What should you do first?",
    "choices": [
      "Begin light braking.",
      "Begin controlled or stab braking.",
      "Stay off the brake until the vehicle slows down on its own."
    ],
    "answer": "Stay off the brake until the vehicle slows down on its own."
  },
  {
    "question": "118. Which of these will help keep an engine cool in hot weather?",
    "choices": [
      "Making sure the engine has the right amount of oil.",
      "Properly adjusted v-belts.",
      "Avoiding high-speed driving.",
      "All of these answers are correct."
    ],
    "answer": "All of these answers are correct."
  },
  {
    "question": "119. When a vehicle is carrying a load at night, which extends four feet or more beyond the rear of the body, there must be at the extreme end of the load.",
    "choices": [
      "1 large red flag.",
      "3 red flags.",
      "2 red lights."
    ],
    "answer": "2 red lights."
  },
  {
    "question": "120. When checking the bus seats, what are you looking for?",
    "choices": [
      "To ensure they are securely fastened to the bus.",
      "To see if they have been removed.",
      "To ensure the seat and back portions are not loose.",
      "All these answers are correct."
    ],
    "answer": "All these answers are correct."
  },
  {
    "question": "121. You must inspect your cargo:",
    "choices": [
      "After every break.",
      "Every 3 hours or 150 miles.",
      "Before starting.",
      "All of these are correct."
    ],
    "answer": "All of these are correct."
  },
  {
    "question": "122. Tie downs must be of the proper type and strength. The combined strength of cargo tie downs must be strong enough to lift:",
    "choices": [
      "One and one-half times the weight of the cargo tied down.",
      "Three times the weight of the cargo tied down.",
      "Twice the weight of the cargo tied down."
    ],
    "answer": "Three times the weight of the cargo tied down."
  },
  {
    "question": "123. Which of these is important to check before driving in the winter?",
    "choices": [
      "Exhaust.",
      "Steering.",
      "Tires."
    ],
    "answer": "Exhaust."
  },
  {
    "question": "124. Tank vehicles are used to carry any liquid and are dangerous to drive because:",
    "choices": [
      "Danger of load surge.",
      "High center of gravity.",
      "Shifting of the load occurs.",
      "All of these are true."
    ],
    "answer": "All of these are true."
  },
  {
    "question": "125. Gross Vehicle Weight Rating (GVWR) means the following?",
    "choices": [
      "Maximum GVW specified by manufacture for a single vehicle including its load.",
      "Maximum GVW specified by the manufacture.",
      "Maximum GVW specified by manufacture for a single vehicle."
    ],
    "answer": "Maximum GVW specified by manufacture for a single vehicle including its load."
  },
  {
    "question": "126. Gross Vehicle Weight (GVW) means the following:",
    "choices": [
      "The total weight of a single vehicle including its load.",
      "Total weight of a single vehicle.",
      "Total weight of the vehicle axle."
    ],
    "answer": "The total weight of a single vehicle including its load."
  },
  {
    "question": "127. Prior to driving, what are some of the items you should check the interior of the bus for?",
    "choices": [
      "School books and student belongings.",
      "A student or other passengers.",
      "Trash and clothing.",
      "All of these are correct."
    ],
    "answer": "All of these are correct."
  },
  {
    "question": "128. How far can the board of education make a student walk to their assigned pick up location?",
    "choices": [
      "1/2 mile.",
      "150 yards.",
      "250 yards."
    ],
    "answer": "1/2 mile."
  },
  {
    "question": "129. There are three types of vehicle inspections, which of these is one of them?",
    "choices": [
      "Post-trip.",
      "En-route.",
      "Pre-trip.",
      "All of these are correct."
    ],
    "answer": "All of these are correct."
  },
  {
    "question": "130. You are checking your brakes and suspension system for a pre-trip inspection. Which of these statements is true?",
    "choices": [
      "Brake pads should not have brake fluid on them.",
      "One missing leaf in a leaf spring can be dangerous.",
      "Brake shoes should be at least 1/32 inch thick.",
      "All of these are true."
    ],
    "answer": "All of these are true."
  },
  {
    "question": "131. You must park on the side of a level, straight, four-lane, divided highway. Where should you place the three reflective triangles?",
    "choices": [
      "One about 50 feet from the rear of the vehicle, one about 100 feet to the rear, and one about 100 feet from the front of the vehicle.",
      "One within 10 feet of the front of the vehicle, one about 200 feet from the front, and one about 100 feet to the rear.",
      "One within 10 feet of the rear of the vehicle, one about 100 feet to the rear, and one about 200 feet to the rear."
    ],
    "answer": "One within 10 feet of the rear of the vehicle, one about 100 feet to the rear, and one about 200 feet to the rear."
  },
  {
    "question": "132. Which of these is a good driving rule for work zones?",
    "choices": [
      "Turn on your flashers/hazard lights.",
      "Use your brake lights to warn drivers behind you.",
      "Drive slowly.",
      "All of these are correct."
    ],
    "answer": "All of these are correct."
  },
  {
    "question": "133. Under loaded front axles can cause the following:",
    "choices": [
      "Too much play in the steering wheel.",
      "Poor traction.",
      "Damage to the tires.",
      "All of these are correct."
    ],
    "answer": "All of these are correct."
  },
  {
    "question": "134. Dry bulk tanks require special care because:",
    "choices": [
      "The load can shift.",
      "They have a high center of gravity.",
      "Both of these are true."
    ],
    "answer": "Both of these are true."
  },
  {
    "question": "135. Overloading can have a bad effect on?",
    "choices": [
      "Speed control.",
      "Steering.",
      "Braking.",
      "All of these are correct."
    ],
    "answer": "All of these are correct."
  },
  {
    "question": "136. No matter how small the cargo is, it should have at least:",
    "choices": [
      "6 tie downs.",
      "2 tie downs.",
      "1 tie down."
    ],
    "answer": "2 tie down."
  },
  {
    "question": "137. As part of your pre-trip inspection, you must:",
    "choices": [
      "Check for poorly balanced weight.",
      "Check if cargo is secured.",
      "Check for overloads.",
      "All of these are correct."
    ],
    "answer": "All of these are correct."
  },
  {
    "question": "138. Which item below lists almost all or all the emergency equipment that is required on a school bus?",
    "choices": [
      "A fire extinguisher, flashlight, fusees, electrical fuses (if your vehicle uses them), a crowbar, emergency triangles, and a first aid kit (with an emergency medical card for each student inside the first aid kit).",
      "A crowbar and fire extinguisher only.",
      "A can of brake fluid, flashlight, and a new bottle of window washer fluid."
    ],
    "answer": "A fire extinguisher, flashlight, fusees, electrical fuses (if your vehicle uses them), a crowbar, emergency triangles, and a first aid kit (with an emergency medical card for each student inside the first aid kit)."
  },
  {
    "question": "139. Cargo that is not loaded or secured properly can cause many problems. Which of these statements is true?",
    "choices": [
      "Other highway users can hit or be hit by loose cargo.",
      "Loose cargo can cause injury to the driver or passengers during a quick stop or crash.",
      "Overloading can damage the vehicle.",
      "All of these are true."
    ],
    "answer": "All of these are true."
  },
  {
    "question": "140. You must drive on a slippery road. Which of these is a good thing to do in such a situation?",
    "choices": [
      "Apply the brakes during turns.",
      "Slow down gradually.",
      "Use a smaller following distance."
    ],
    "answer": "Slow down gradually."
  },
  {
    "question": "141. Brake 'fade':",
    "choices": [
      "Can be corrected by letting up on the brakes for 1-2 seconds and then reapplying them.",
      "Only occurs with drum brakes.",
      "Can be caused by the brakes becoming too hot."
    ],
    "answer": "Can be caused by the brakes becoming too hot."
  },
  {
    "question": "142. The biggest problem with a broken exhaust system is that it may let poison fumes into the vehicle's cab.",
    "choices": ["True.", "False."],
    "answer": "True."
  },
  {
    "question": "143. What is the most important reason for doing a vehicle inspection?",
    "choices": [
      "Federal and State regulations require you to inspect your vehicle.",
      "Safety for yourself and others.",
      "A vehicle defect found during inspection can save you problems later.",
      "All of these are correct."
    ],
    "answer": "All of these are correct."
  },
  {
    "question": "144. You should have a minimum of tread on your steering tires.",
    "choices": ["1/4 inch.", "4/32 inch.", "2/32 inch."],
    "answer": "4/32 inch."
  },
  {
    "question": "145. When taking a break in the middle of your trip, you should check:",
    "choices": [
      "Critical items: windshield wiper blades, heater, and defroster.",
      "Call in and check with dispatch.",
      "Critical items such as: tires, brakes, and cargo tie-downs."
    ],
    "answer": "Critical items such as: tires, brakes, and cargo tie-downs."
  },
  {
    "question": "146. Which of these is correct regarding brake shoes:",
    "choices": [
      "Brake shoes should be larger than a quarter on the steering axle.",
      "Brake shoes should not be worn dangerously thin.",
      "Brake shoes should have the same thickness as a penny."
    ],
    "answer": "Brake shoes should not be worn dangerously thin."
  },
  {
    "question": "147. What items should be checked for safety on the steering column?",
    "choices": [
      "Up to 1/4 of the steering parts may be broken.",
      "Steering arms should not have missing nut, bolts or cotter keys.",
      "Steering arms should not have mismatched, bent or cracked lug nuts."
    ],
    "answer": "Steering arms should not have missing nut, bolts or cotter keys."
  },
  {
    "question": "148. Measuring BAC (Blood Alcohol Concentration) is done by measuring a person's:",
    "choices": ["Age.", "Height.", "Body Weight."],
    "answer": "Body Weight."
  },
  {
    "question": "149. Your truck has a dual air system and one of the systems loses its pressure. What will happen?",
    "choices": [
      "The manual slack adjusters of the S-cam brakes will not be set properly.",
      "Brake drums will not be fully pressurized.",
      "Either the front or back brake will not be fully operational."
    ],
    "answer": "Either the front or back brake will not be fully operational."
  },
  {
    "question": "150. When getting in to start the engine and inspect inside the cab you must:",
    "choices": [
      "Make sure the parking brake is on and put the gearshift in neutral (or park if automatic).",
      "Start the engine and listen for unusual noises.",
      "Both of these answers are correct."
    ],
    "answer": "Both of these answers are correct."
  },
  {
    "question": "151. When preparing to do a pre-trip inspection you must check to see that the parking brakes are on and/or chocked.",
    "choices": ["True.", "False."],
    "answer": "True."
  },
  {
    "question": "152. The oil pressure gauge should come up to normal within how long after starting the engine?",
    "choices": ["Minutes.", "Seconds.", "It does not matter."],
    "answer": "Seconds."
  },
  {
    "question": "153. You should check the following for looseness, sticking, damage, or improper settings:",
    "choices": [
      "Steering wheel and Transmission controls.",
      "Accelerator, brakes, and clutch pedals.",
      "Both of these answers are correct."
    ],
    "answer": "Both of these answers are correct."
  },
  {
    "question": "154. After inspecting mirrors and windshields for cracks, dirt, and illegal stickers, or other obstructions to your vision, you should:",
    "choices": [
      "Look in the mirror to see if you look good.",
      "Clean and adjust as necessary.",
      "Not worry about any of it."
    ],
    "answer": "Clean and adjust as necessary."
  },
  {
    "question": "155. When checking lights you should:",
    "choices": [
      "Make sure that the parking brake is set.",
      "Turn off the engine and take the key with you.",
      "Turn on the headlights and four-way flashers.",
      "All of these are correct."
    ],
    "answer": "All of these are correct."
  },
  {
    "question": "156. What should the wheel bearing seals be checked for?",
    "choices": [
      "Color of paint used on cover.",
      "Cleanliness.",
      "Hub oil level and no leaks."
    ],
    "answer": "Hub oil level and no leaks."
  },
  {
    "question": "157. How many red reflective triangles should you carry?",
    "choices": ["1.", "3.", "4."],
    "answer": "3."
  },
  {
    "question": "158. How do you test the hydraulic brakes for leaks?",
    "choices": [
      "Pump the brake pedal three times, then apply firm pressure to the pedal and hold for five seconds. The pedal should not move.",
      "Drive 20 mph and slam on the brakes.",
      "Drive slowly and pump the brake pedal. Make sure it doesn't hit the floor."
    ],
    "answer": "Pump the brake pedal three times, then apply firm pressure to the pedal and hold for five seconds. The pedal should not move."
  },
  {
    "question": "159. Why put the starter key in your pocket during the pre-trip inspection?",
    "choices": [
      "So you don't lose it.",
      "So no one moves the vehicle.",
      "For your safety."
    ],
    "answer": "For your safety."
  }

]

